Are you alright, Marumo?
（薫）大丈夫？　マルモ。
Sorry. I might have gave you my cold.
（友樹）ごめんね 僕の風邪　うつしちゃったかも。
I'm alright. You guys go to school.
あっ　大丈夫だから。 お前ら　学校　行ってこい。
Yeah, but...
うん　でも。
I'll watch him so don't worry.
（ムック）僕が見てるから大丈夫。
Okay, we'll leave him to Mook then.
うん　じゃ　ムックに任せた。
-What? To the dog? -See you later.
えっ？　犬に？ いってきます。
-We're going. -Hey, you guys, hey.
あら　あら　ちょっと　お前ら　おい。
What you nodding for.
何　うなずいてんだ。
-Morning.
（彩）あっ　おはよう。 （友樹・薫）おはよう。
Marumo
あのね　マルモが→
-caught a cold and can't get up. -What?
風邪ひいて起きられないの。 （彩）えっ？
So please take care of Marumo for us.
だから　マルモのこと よろしくお願いします。
Okay, got it. Go carefully, now.
うん　分かった。 気を付けて行ってらっしゃい。
-See you later.
いってきます。
I'm coming in.
≪（ドアの開く音） ≪（陽介）邪魔するよ。→
Hey, I heard you weren't feeling well. Shall I make you some porridge?
おう　体調　悪いんだって？ おかゆでも作るか。
Thanks, but I have to go to work.
いえ　すいません。 でも　会社に行かないと。
Are you alright?
（陽介）お前　大丈夫か？→
Aren't your cheeks swollen?
あれ？　お前 何か　ほっぺた腫れてない？
What? Huh?
えっ？　えっ？　ちょっと。
-It's just your imagination. -No, I tell you, they're swollen,
気のせいでしょ。 （陽介）いやいや　腫れてるって。→
It wouldn't be mumps, would it?
あっ　まさか おたふくじゃねえだろうな。
-What? -I guess it wouldn't be.
えっ？ （陽介）あっ　違うか。→
Normally, you would've had it when you were a kid, right?
普通　ちっちゃいころに かかってるもんな。
Right. Don't scare me like that.
ですよ。　あ～　びっくりした　もう。
Don't overexert yourself.
（陽介）あんまり無理すんなよ。→
Okay, I'm leaving then.
うん。　あっ　じゃ　行くわ。 はい。
Call me if you need anything.
（陽介）うん 何かあったら　声　掛けて。
Thanks.
あっ　すいません。 （陽介）はい。
I have to go for counseling today too.
あっ　今日 カウンセリングも行かなくちゃ。
-Hello, this is Takagi. -Hey, Mom? It's Mamoru.
[TEL]（節子）はい　高木です。 あっ　お母ちゃん？　護だけど。
What happened? How have you been?
[TEL]あっ　どうしたの？　元気？
I've already had mumps, haven't I?
俺さ　おたふくって かかったことあるよね。
Once you've had it, you can't get it anymore, right?
あれって　一度やれば もう　かかんないんだよな。
Gosh, I think you've had it.
[TEL]さあ　やったと思うけど。→
Or was that chicken pox? Maybe it was measles.
あれ？　水ぼうそうだったかな。 あっ　はしかだったかも。
Don't mothers usually remember stuff like that?
そんなの覚えてるだろ　普通。
It's been so long, I forgot.
[TEL]昔のことだから 忘れちゃったわよ。→
It's not a wah hah hah matter. Try to remember.
ウハハハハ…。 ウハハハじゃなくて思い出して。
If a stranger starts talking to you,
（杉下）知らない人から 声を掛けられても→
don't trust him and go with him.
信用して　ついていかないこと。
If you feel you're in danger, scream and run away.
危険だと思ったら 大声で叫んで逃げること。
You got that?
分かったかな。 （一同）は～い。
You all have the personal alarm I passed out, right?
うん　渡した防犯ブザー みんな　ちゃんと持ってるよな。
I have mine on my ransel.
（健太）僕　ランドセルに付けてる。
-Me too.
わたしも。 （まなみ）わたしも。
I'm hanging mine from my neck. Look.
僕は首から下げてる。　ほら。
-What are you doing? -I'm sorry.
何やってんの。 ごめんなさい。
As you heard, it makes a loud noise,
（杉下）と　こういうふうに 大きな音が出るから→
so remember to be careful.
みんな　覚えとくように。
Yes.
はい。
Doctor, recently
先生　最近じゃ→
he even says things like "I like this dog food better."
ドッグフードは　こっちの方がいいなんて言うんですよ。
-The dog? -The dog.
（桜子）犬が？ 犬が。
We all have conversations with the dog, and
犬と一緒に みんなで会話もしてるし→
sometimes I find myself talking to him.
時々　自分から 話し掛けちゃうこともあるんです。
Is this really the voice of my subconscious self?
これって　ホントに 俺の心の声なんでしょうか。
-I've never heard of a case like this. -What? Doctor, what?
今までにないケースだわ。 えっ？　先生　えっ？
Oh, nothing. Let's see how it goes for a while.
あっ　いえ もう少し様子を見てみましょう。
Just take it easy.
気を楽にして。
By the way, Takagi-san, could that swelling
ところで高木さん　その腫れ もしかして→
possibly be epidemic parotitis?
流行性耳下腺炎じゃないですか？ はい？
-In other words, mumps. -Mumps?
つまり　おたふくかぜです。 おたふく？
-That mumps?
（民子）おたふく？ （凛花）あの　おたふく？
-That mumps. -Is he a kid?
（鮫島）あの　おたふくだ。 （真島）子供かよ。
I'm guessing he won't be back to work for at least a week.
（鮫島）１週間は 仕事に出てこられないだろうな。
My son had it too, but it's very painful.
（民子）うちの息子も　やったけど あれ　つらいんですよね。
High fever lasts for several days and this area around here swells up a lot.
高熱が何日も続くし　この辺が ものすごい腫れちゃうし。
That's awful.
（凛花）えっ　大変。
Takagi-kun lives alone, doesn't he?
（鮫島）高木君は 一人暮らしだったよな。
Huh? Yes, he does.
えっ？　ええ　そうですけど。
Why don't someone go see how he's doing?
（鮫島）誰か 見舞いに行ってやったらどうだ。
I-I-I'll go. Please let me go.
（真島）おっ　おっ　俺　行きます。 俺に行かしてください。
Why are you so eager?
何　張り切ってんの？
I'm not...
いや　別に。
-Itadakimasu.
（２人）いただきます。 （一同）いただきます。
Tomoki-kun, do you dislike carrots?
（はるか）友樹君 ニンジン　嫌いなの？
-Yeah. -You're not supposed to leave any food.
うん。 （まなみ）いけないんだよ　残しちゃ。
You have to eat carrots too.
（はるか）ニンジン 食べなきゃいけないんだよ。
-That's right, that's right. -Wh-wh-
（男の子）そうだよ　そうだよ。 （杉下）どっ　どっ→
what's going on? You have to eat everything, you know.
どうした　どうした？ おっ　駄目だぞ　全部　食べなきゃ。
The school says you don't have to eat everything because
あのな　最近は 保護者からクレームが来るから→
of complaints from the parents, but I don't agree.
残していいことになってるけど 先生は反対だ。→
If you have likes and dislikes, you won't be strong and healthy.
好き嫌いをなくさないと 丈夫な子になれないぞ。
Okay.
はい。
Tomoki.
友樹。
Onee-chan.
お姉ちゃん。
I guess I have no choice.
もう　しょうがないな。
Thanks. Why aren't we alike even though we're twins?
ありがとう。　どうして 双子なのに似なかったんだろう。
It's strange, huh?
不思議だね。
Be careful. Straight ahead. Keep it straight.
（陽介）ぶつけるな。　真っすぐ 真っすぐ　真っすぐ　真っすぐ。
-Like this? -But just think.
こう？ （陽介）いや　しかし→
He really did have mumps.
本当に おたふくかぜだったとはな。
He must not have had it when he was a child.
（彩）子供んときに かかってなかったのね。
Seriously, what an oddball he is, that guy.
珍しいやつだよな　まったく。
Takagi-san, you sleep in this room for a while, okay?
高木さんは 当分　こっちで寝てくださいね。
It won't be good if you give it to the kids.
子供たちに　うつすと　まずいんで。
Yes, thanks.
はい　すいません。
We're home.
≪（ドアの開く音） （薫・友樹）ただいま。
-Hi. -What happened?
（陽介・彩）おかえり。 あれ？　どうしたの？
You guys stay in this room
（陽介）お前たちな　しばらくは→
-for a few days, okay? -Why?
こっちの部屋にいてくれな。 何で？
Takagi-san's sleeping in the other room. He has mumps.
（彩）あっちで高木さんが寝てるの。おたふくかぜだったのよ。
His cheeks are swollen and he has a high fever.
ほっぺが腫れて熱が出て大変なの。え～。
You won't want to catch it, so make sure you don't go in that room.
うつるといけないから 絶対に入っちゃ駄目よ。
-Okay. -Don't come in here.
うん。 ≪来ちゃ駄目だぞ。
Are you alright, Marumo?
大丈夫？　マルモ。
Yeah, I'm fine.
ああ　大丈夫だ。
Marumo.
マルモ。
We'll come up frequently to see how things are going,
（彩）わたしたちも ちょくちょく見に来るから→
so don't worry. Okay?
心配しないで。　ねっ。
Okay.
うん　分かった。 （彩）うん。
I wonder if Marumo's alright.
大丈夫かな　マルモ。
-I'm gonna take a peak. -No, you can't.
ちょっと　のぞいてみる。 あっ　だっ　駄目。
If you open the door, Marumo's going to turn into a crane.
開けたら マルモが鶴に変身しちゃうんだよ。
Crane?! Okay, I won't.
鶴！　わっ　分かった。
-Let's finish our homework. -Okay.
うん　宿題やっちゃおう。 うん　うん。
Who could it be?
誰だろう。
Shall we go see?
行ってみる？ うん。
Mamoru? Are you there, Mamoru?
≪（節子）護？　いるの？　護。
Who is this?
どちらさまですか？ （節子）えっ？
Who are you?
んっ？ 誰？
-Who are you? -Who are you guys?
あなたたちこそ誰？
You too, Oba-chan, who are you? -But, isn't this
おばちゃんも誰？ （節子）えっ　だって　ここ→
-Takagi Mamoru's house? -It is.
高木　護のうちでしょ？ そうだよ。
-What do you mean it is? -Mom?
そうだよって　どういうこと？ 母ちゃん？
-Sasakura-kun's children? -Yeah.
（節子）笹倉君の子供？ うん。
But why you?
（節子）でも　何で　あんたが？
It's not that they don't have relatives, right?
親戚だって いないわけないでしょ。
Oh, I remember he had a brother.
あっ お兄さんだっていたじゃない。
He did, but the kids were about to be
そうだけど　親戚に預けたら→
separated if they went with their relatives.
あの子たち　ばらばらになっちゃうとこだったんだ。
Still, don't you think you're being irresponsible taking them in?
だからって　あんたが預かるなんて無責任じゃないの？
It's hard enough to raise your own children,
あのね　自分の子供を育てんだって大変なのよ。
let alone other people's children.
それを　ひとさまの子供なんて。
And two of them at that.
しかも２人よ。
It's just not possible.
もう　無理に決まってるわよ。
You don't know that until I try it.
そんなの やってみなきゃ分かんないだろ。
And if something happened,
それで　もし何かあったら→
how are you going to apologize to Sasakura-kun?
笹倉君に どう　おわびするつもりよ。
That's... Seriously...
それは。 ハァ　まったく　もう。
I heard you weren't feeling well, so I came to Tokyo,
具合が悪いっていうから 久しぶりに上京したのも→
but look at this.
こんなことになってて。
I won't approve of this.
わたしは認めませんからね。
Take those children back immediately.
あの子たち　すぐに返しなさい。
In the first place, while you're lying here sick,
だいたい　あんたが こうやって病気で寝てる間→
who's taking care of those children?
あの子たちの面倒 誰が見るっていうの？
Mom, why don't take it easy and stay here for 2 or 3 days?
あっ　母ちゃん ２～３日　ゆっくりしてけば？
What?
はっ？
Why do I have to be doing this.
何で　わたしが　こんなこと。
Are you hungry?
あっ。 （節子）あっ　おなか　すいた？→
Oh, it's that time already. We'll have to make dinner, won't we?
ああ　もう　そんな時間か。 晩ご飯　作んなくちゃね。
There's nothing decent in here.
（節子）う～ん ろくな物　入ってないな　もう。
What do you want to do about dinner?
（彩）ねえ　夕飯　どうする？
-She's Marumo's mommy. -Nice to meet you.
マルモのママだよ。 あっ　初めまして。
I'm the daughter of the landlord downstairs. My name's Hatanaka Aya.
あの　わたし　下の大家の娘で 畑中　彩といいます。
Thank you for putting up with Mamoru all the time.
いつも 護が　お世話になっております。
She's going to make dinner for us.
ご飯　作ってくれるんだって。
Oh really, how nice. You're okay then, huh?
あっ　そっか　よかったね。 あっ　じゃ　大丈夫だね。
I'm sorry. They must impose on you a lot.
あっ　すいません。 何だか　ご迷惑　掛けてるみたいで。
No, not at all. Good bye then.
あっ　いえいえ。　じゃ　失礼します。
-How were the kids doing? -Looks like they're fine.
（陽介）子供たち　どうだった？ （彩）うん　大丈夫みたい。→
Takagi-san's mother was there.
高木さんのお母さんが 来られてたから。
Mother?
（陽介）お母さん？
Has he told her the whole story
おい　あいつ ちゃんと　話　してあるのか→
-about the kids? -I'm not sure.
子供たちのこと。 （彩）んっ　どうなんだろ。
-She'd be surprised if she found out suddenly, huh? -That's for sure.
いきなりじゃ　びっくりするよね。 （陽介）そりゃ驚くわ。
Most mothers wouldn't approve.
まあ　普通なら反対するな。
Hello, welcome.
≪（戸の開く音） （陽介）はい　いらっしゃい。
Good evening.
（真島）どうも　こんばんは。
Oh, you're from Takagi-san's office.
あっ　あっ　高木さんの会社の方。
You remembered? I'm Mashima.
（真島）おっ　覚えててくれました？真島です。
I'm so pleased you remember me.
あ～　覚えててくれて　うれしいな。
I'm here to visit Takagi-san.
あの　高木さんの お見舞いに来たんですけど。
This is a nice restaurant. Are you always here...
あ～　すてきな　お店ですね。 あの　いつも　お店には…。
If you came to see Takagi Mamoru, his room's on the 2nd floor.
高木　護だったら　２階だよ。
Ah, yes.
あっ　はい。
So her name's Aya-san. She's pretty, isn't she?
（真島）彩さんっていうんですか 奇麗っすよね。
I wonder if she has a boyfriend.
彼氏とか　いんのかな。
She wouldn't happen to be after you, would she?
まさか 高木さん狙ってるなんてことは。
No she wouldn't.
ねえよ　もう。
Or rather, why are you here?
つうか　お前　何しに来たんだよ。
To see how you're doing, of course.
もちろん 高木さんのお見舞いですよ。
But it's good that your mother's here.
でも　お母さん来てくれてて よかったっすね。
I guess, although her nagging's killing me.
まあな 口うるさくて嫌になるけどな。
A little while ago too, she was nagging about the kids.
さっきもさ 子供たちのこと反対されてさ。
She told me to return them to their relatives.
親戚に返せって。
Well, I can see how they would be tough to manage by yourself.
まあ 高木さん１人じゃ大変ですもんね。
It would be easier if you had a wife or girlfriend, but
奥さんとか彼女が いればいいけどって→
you have nothing of that sort, do you?
そういう話もないでしょ？
Sorry for not having any.
なくて悪かったな。
And your face is all swollen.
おたふくで顔は腫れてるし。
You'd better not tell Makimura-san about this.
お前 牧村さんに　このこと言うなよ。
I wouldn't know what to do if she came anyway. I can't show her my face,
お見舞いに来られても困るしな。 この顔は見せられないし→
and what would happen if she found out about the kids.
子供たちのことバレても あれだかんな。
I won't tell her, but I seriously doubt
いや　言いませんけど まず来ないでしょ→
-if Makimura-san would visit you. -Fantasy like that's necessary too
牧村さんが　お見舞いには。 そういう妄想も必要なんだよ→
at times like this in my weakened condition.
こういう弱ってるときはさ。
Here you go, eat up.
（節子）どうぞ　召し上がれ。
-Itadakima~su. -Itadakimasu.
（薫・友樹）いただきま～す。 （節子）いただきます。
This is awesome. The fridge was almost empty, but you made all this.
すごい。　冷蔵庫　空っぽだったのにこんなに　いっぱい。
-Delicious. -Really? I'm glad.
おいしい。 （節子）そう？　よかった。
-We usually have the goma shio boss. -Goma shio boss?
いつもは　ごま塩の親分なんだよ。 ごま塩の親分？
This one.
これだよ。 （節子）んっ？
-Thank you, Boss. -Thanks.
親分　お疲れさまです。 お疲れっす。
But how terrible. Is he only feeding you this kind of thing?
でも　やあね。　あの子 こんな物しか食べさしてないの？
-It's good. -Even if it's good...
おいしいよ。 いくら　おいしくたって。
Tomoki-kun, don't you like carrots?
友樹君　ニンジン　嫌いなの？
-No. -He got scolded at school during lunch too.
うん。 給食のときも怒られたの。
I don't have to eat it when I'm home, do I?
おうちなら残してもいいでしょ？
It's okay with me.
（節子）んっ　うん わたしは構わないけど。
What a relief.
よかった。
By the way, where's your chopsticks and rice bowls?
あれ？　そういえば　あなたたちの お箸と　お茶わんは？
-This is all we have. -Really? Seriously...
これしかないよ。 え～　まったく　もう→
He's just not very thoughtful about these things.
そういうところが 気が利かないのよね。
It's hard to eat, isn't it?
食べづらいでしょう。
Okay, let's go shopping tomorrow.
そうだ　ねえ あした　買いに行きましょう。
Okay. Yay!
（薫・友樹）はい。　やった～。
Mamoru, I'm going shopping with the kids.
（節子）護　子供たちと 買い物　行ってくるから。
-Okay. -Will Marumo be alright?
≪分かった。 マルモ　大丈夫かな。
Will he be alright?
大丈夫かな。
I brought him some porridge a little while ago, so he should be fine.
さっき　おかゆ持ってったから 大丈夫でしょ。
While you're there, buy Mook's food too.
ついでに　あの ムックのご飯も買ってきて。
Really. He doesn't make much money and he's even taking care of a dog.
ったく　もう。　稼ぎも少ないのに 犬まで預かって。
Marumo gets mad when we eat his ice cream.
マルモって アイス食べると怒るんだよ。
That's so immature of him.
（節子）あら　大人げないわね。
Did he always like ice cream?
小さいころから アイス　好きだったの？
Yes. Like when he caught a cold,
（節子）そう 風邪ひいたときなんかね→
he'd always say "I want ice cream" and made a big fuss.
いつも 「アイス食べたい」って騒いでた。
Shall we buy some today?
じゃ　今日も買ってく？
Yes, let's do that.
（節子）そうね　うん　そうしようか。
Yay!
やった。
Tomoki, you said that because you want ice cream.
友樹　自分が食べたいだけじゃん。
You got me.
ヘヘヘ　バレちゃった。
Ice cream.
（薫・友樹）アイス。 （節子）はいはい。
We want ice cream.
（薫・友樹）食べたいな。
-Premium. -What?
（薫・友樹）プレミアム。 （節子）えっ？
Ice cream.
（薫・友樹）アイス。 （節子）はいはい。
Yay! They're so cute.
やった　カワイイね。
I'm going to have seconds with this.
うん。　これで　お代わりするぞ。
Thank you, Marumo Mommy. Thank you.
マルモママ　ありがとう。 ありがとう。
-Alright. -What are you making for dinner?
あっ　はい。 夕ご飯　何　作るの？
Hamburger. Go play until dinner.
（節子）ハンバーグよ。 それまで遊んでなさい。
Yay. Hamburger.
やった。 （薫・友樹）ハンバーグ。
Onee-chan, let's go to the park.
お姉ちゃん　公園　遊びに行こうよ。
Okay.
うん　いいよ。
-Are you two going to be okay by yourselves? -It's close by.
（節子）えっ？　２人だけで大丈夫？すぐそこだから。
-Are you sure? -Marumo, we're going out to play.
（節子）そう？ マルモ　遊びに行ってくる。
Oh, take the personal alarm with you.
≪あっ あれ持ってけよ　防犯ブザー。
Okay.
うん　分かった。
If a suspicious person starts talking to you, pull on it.
怪しい人に　声　掛けられたら すぐ引っ張んだぞ。
-Okay.
は～い。
What a terrible world this has become. To have to teach them to be suspicious of people.
嫌な世の中ね　人を疑うこと 教えなきゃなんないんだから。
That's the way things are nowadays.
今は　しょうがないんだよ。
-We're going then. -See you later.
じゃ　いってきます。 いってきます。
Beware of strangers.
（節子）怪しい人に気を付けるのよ。
-Okay.
分かった。 はい。
Let's go to that park we went the other day.
ねえねえ この前　行った　公園　行こうよ。
Okay.
うん。
Excuse me.
（男性）ちょっと。
-Who is he? -I don't know.
誰？ 知らない。
What's that?
≪（防犯ブザーの音） 何だ？
It's going off. Mamoru, it's going off.
（節子）はっ　鳴ってる 護　鳴ってる。
I heard, I heard... Why are you holding that?
聞こえてる　聞こえて… いや　何それ　持ってくの？
What's going on?
お前ら　どうした。 （陽介）おい　どうした。
How do you stop this?
どうするんだ？　これ。
Hello, everyone.
やあ　皆さん。
Chief.
室長。 （一同）えっ？
I'm sorry.
（薫・友樹）ごめんなさい。
I thought you had something going on, but
何か事情があるとは 思ってたけど→
I never would have guessed you were taking care of your late friend's children.
まさか　亡くなった友達の お子さんを預かっているとはね。
I was surprised too.
わたしも　もう　びっくりで。
I don't even have grandchildren yet.
孫の顔だって まだ見てないんですよ。
Mom, go to the other room please.
お母ちゃん　あっち行ってて。 えっ？
Okay, okay. Please make yourself at home.
あっ　はいはい。 どうぞ　ごゆっくり。
I'm sorry I didn't tell you sooner.
黙ってて　すいませんでした。
And so?
それで？
What are your plans for the future?
これから どうするつもりなのかな？
I'd like to go on living with those kids.
あの子たちと 一緒に住んでこうと思ってます。
I'm sorry. That's why I'm not sure what I should do.
すいません だから　どうしようかなって。
I don't want to be a burden to my colleagues.
同僚の　みんなに　迷惑 掛けるわけにもいかないですし。
Is it possible to get a transfer to a department
残業のない部署っていうか そういうとこに→
where I won't have to work overtime?
回してもらうことって できますかね。
You're serious about living with those children, then?
本気なんだね？ あの子たちと暮らしていくこと。
Yes.
はい。
Is it okay if I sit comfortably?
あのさ　足　崩していいかな。
Oh, sorry. Please do.
あっ　すいません どっ　どっ　どうぞ　どうぞ。
-I have sciatica. -Oh, I forgot that you did. Sorry.
座骨神経痛で。 あっ　そうでした　すいません。
Then just stay with our department.
だったら うちの部署にいればいいよ。
-Pardon me? -Customer Service Department
はい？ お客様相談室は　→
stops taking calls at 5 PM. After that, you just have to wrap things up.
１７時で電話の案内が終わる。 後は残務処理だ。
If you can get everyone to cooperate,
みんなの協力が得られれば→
I think you can manage to make it.
何とか やっていけるんじゃないかな。
Chief.
室長。
Thank you.
ありがとうございます。
But you sure choose to live the hard way, don't you?
しかし　不器用な男だね　君も。 はっ？
You could have chosen an easier path.
もっと楽な生き方だって あるだろうに。
-Hello.
（かな）お疲れさまです。 （一同）お疲れさまです。
Is Takagi-san here?
（かな）高木さん いらっしゃいますか？
He's out sick with the mumps.
（民子）それが　おたふくかぜで 休んでるんですよね。
-Mumps? -It's unusual, isn't it,
えっ　おたふく。 （凛花）珍しいですよね→
to get it at that age. Did you need something?
あの年で　かかるなんて。 （民子）何か　ご用でしたか？
Well, yes...
（かな）あっ　ええ→
I wanted him to take a look at the report of the last business trip.
先日の出張の報告書を 見てもらおうと思いまして。
I think he'll be off for about a week.
（凛花）１週間くらい 休むと思います。
-I see. -Oh, Makimura-san.
（かな）あっ　そうですか。 （真島）あっ　牧村さん。
There's absolutely no need for you to go visit him.
お見舞いとか まったく必要ないですからね。
Takagi-san's face is all swollen like this.
高木さんの顔も こんな腫れちゃって。
Is it that bad?
あっ　そんなに　ひどいんですか？
It's bad, real bad. He looks like something out of a horror movie.
う～　ひどい　ひどい もう　ホラー映画みたいですよ。
-Horror? -That's scary.
ホラー？ （凛花）やだ　怖い。
So it would be best you stayed away from him for a while.
だから 当分は近づかない方がいいですよ。
It's good.
おいしい。
It's good. Marumo Mommy, you're awesome.
おいしい。　マルモママ　すげえ。
I'm so glad.
あ～　よかった。
Poor Marumo. He can't eat.
マルモ　かわいそうだね 食べられないなんて。
But I made a lot so
（節子）うん。 でも　いっぱい作ったから→
he can eat it when he gets better.
良くなったら食べられるわよ。
I guess so.
うん　そうだね。
What kind of a kid was Marumo?
ねえ マルモって　どんな子だったの？
Tell us, tell us.
えっ？ 聞きたい　聞きたい。
Well, let's see. He always liked baseball.
うん　そうね 昔から野球が大好きでね→
He'd be out in the field playing until dusk.
日が暮れるまで 原っぱで遊んでたわね。
With Daddy?
パパと一緒に？
Yes.  He was really close to Sasakura-kun.
（節子）そう　笹倉君と すっごく　仲　良くってね→
They were always together, like brothers, doing foolish things.
兄弟みたいに　いっつも一緒にいてもう　バカなことばっかり。
Like breaking a neighbor's window while playing baseball, and
野球して　近所んちの窓ガラス 割っちゃったり→
oh, that's right, they dug a huge pitfall in the schoolyard,
それから　そうそう　校庭に こんな大きな落とし穴　掘って→
but then a teacher fell in it.
そしたらね　先生がね そこに落っこっちゃったの。→
They were bad boys.
アハハハハ…。 え～　悪い子だね。
They were, weren't they.
そうだよね。 うん。
They definitely weren't good boys.
（節子）うん 決して　いい子じゃなかったよね。
I never saw either one of them working on
２人とも 学校の宿題なんて　やってんの→
their homework.
見たことなかったわよ。 え～→
But he always tells us to do our homework.
わたしたちには 宿題しろって言うのに。
Marumo's not fair.
マルモ　ずるい。
-Not fair. -Not fair
ずるい。
Are they badmouthing me?
何か　俺の悪口　言ってねえか？
You ate all your hamburger.
（節子）んっ ハンバーグ　全部　食べたのね。
Yes. It was good.
うん　おいしかったよ。
Tomoki-kun, it looks like you can eat carrots, huh?
友樹君 ニンジン食べられるんじゃない？
-What? -There were carrots
えっ？ 入ってたのよ　ニンジン。→
in the hamburger. I chopped them real small and put them in there.
ハンバーグん中に。 細かく刻んで入れといたの。
No, really?
えっ　嘘　そうなの？
I couldn't tell.
分かんなかった。 （節子）アハハハ。
Mamoru didn't like carrots either when he was little.
護もね　ちっちゃいとき ニンジン大嫌いでね→
But when I chopped it real fine and mixed it in, he couldn't tell and ate it.
でも細かく刻んで入れたら 分かんないで食べちゃったの。
So I can eat carrots.
僕　大丈夫なんだ　ニンジン。
Aren't you glad?
よかったね。
Sasakura-kun used to come to our house all the time
笹倉君も よく　うちに遊びに来てね→
and ate this hamburger too.
このハンバーグ食べてたのよ。
Daddy used to like this hamburger too.
パパも好きだったんだ このハンバーグ。
I want to see Daddy.
何か僕 パパに会いたくなっちゃった。
What?
えっ？
I want to talk with Daddy.
パパと　お話ししたいな。
Yes, but that's impossible because he's in heaven.
うん　でも無理だよ　天国だから。
Heaven's far away, isn't it?
天国って遠いんでしょ？
Yes, it is.
そうね。
Mamoru, are you up?
護　起きてる？
Yeah.
ああ。
You know. What?
ねえ。 んっ？
-It's about those children.
あの子たちのことだけどね。
You should have their relatives take care of them after all.
やっぱり 親戚の方に預かってもらいなさい。
You can't take Sasakura-kun's place.
あんたに 笹倉君の代わりはできないわよ。
-But Mom... -I'm not
いや　母ちゃん　それ…。 あんたのことを→
talking about you.
言ってんじゃないの。　ねっ。
I'm saying this for the children's sake.
あの子たちのためを思って 言ってるの。
As things are, all you can do is make them feel lonely.
このままじゃ　あの子たちに 寂しい思いをさせるだけよ。
-Mom. -You can't raise children all by yourself.
母ちゃん。 子育てなんて　１人じゃ　絶対　無理。
Of course, it's a different story if you had someone who'd marry you.
そりゃ　あんたに　お嫁さんでも 来てくれりゃ　別だけど。
But you don't have anyone like that, do you?
いないでしょ？　そんな人。
Anyway, talk it over with Sasakura-kun's brother again.
とにかく　笹倉君のお兄さんと もう一度　話し合いなさい。
If you won't, I'll go talk to him.
あんたが話さないんだったら わたしの方から話すから。
Alright?
ねっ　いいわね。
-Is Daddy sleeping here? -Yes.
ここでパパが眠ってるの？ （節子）そうよ。
Then is this heaven?
じゃ　ここが天国？
No, this isn't heaven.
（節子）ううん　天国じゃないの。
But when you feel like talking to your daddy, you can come here and talk to him.
でもね　パパと話したくなったら ここへ来て話したらいいわ。
You voice will definitely reach your daddy in heaven.
きっと天国のパパに届くわよ。
Okay.
へえ。 分かった。
Okay, let's go.
うん　行こう。
This is it here.
あっ　ここだわ　ほら。
Shall we clean up the grave so that your daddy
パパが 安心して天国で暮らせるように→
and rest peacefully in heaven?
お墓　奇麗にしましょうか。
Yes.
≪（ノック） はい。
Excuse me.
お邪魔します。
How do you feel?
お加減　いかがですか？
Here. Dad told me to check up on you.
あっ　これ お父さんが　様子　見てこいって。
Thanks. The fever's gone down.
すいません。 熱は引いてきたんですけど。
That's good.
あっ　それなら　よかった。
You must be relieved that
あっ　でも お母さんが　いらしてくれて→
your mother's here.
ホントに　よかったですね。
She's taking good care of the kids.
２人の面倒も見てくれるし。
Yes.
はい。
Is something wrong?
どうかしたんですか？
My mom's telling me to take the kids back to their relatives.
おふくろ あの子たちを親戚に返せって。
-What? -She said
えっ？ 俺１人じゃ→
I won't be able to raise the kids by myself.
子育てなんて　絶対　無理だって。
But Takagi-san, you're trying so hard to do everything you can.
いや　でも　高木さん すごく頑張ってるじゃないですか。
But I couldn't say anything back to her.
だけど 言い返せなかったんですよね。
When she said "Do you think a man can raise kids by himself?"
「男手一つで 育てられると思ってんのか」
She told me "all you can do is make them feel lonely."
「あの子たちが　寂しい思い するだけだ」って言われて。
But if you didn't take care of them,
だけど　高木さんがいなかったら→
the kids would be separated.
あの子たちは　ばらばらに なっちゃうじゃないですか。
Of course I want to
もちろん　俺は　このまま→
go on living with those kids too.
あの子たちと 一緒に暮らしていきたいです。
But I'm probably too flaky in my mom's eyes.
でも　おふくろにしてみれば 俺は頼りないんだろうな。
Thank you.
ありがとう。
Okay, put your hands together like this.
じゃあね こうやって　手　合わせるのよ。
Sasakura-kun.
笹倉君。
Daddy.
パパ。
Daddy, I've been meaning to tell you.
あのね　パパ。 薫　パパに言おうと思ってたんだ。
Marumo's letting us live with him.
今　マルモが 一緒にいてくれるんだよ。
A dog called Mook's with us too.
うん　ムックって犬も一緒だよ。
I was almost separated from Tomoki, but
友樹と　ばらばらに なっちゃいそうだったのに→
Marumo told us we could be together.
マルモが「一緒にいていい」って 言ってくれたの。
And the ransel you promised us,
それと パパと約束してたランドセル→
Marumo bought them for us.
マルモが買ってくれたよ。
Marumo even put a heart on mine.
ハートのマークも マルモが付けてくれたの。
And he plays catch with us too.
それに 一緒にキャッチボールもしたよ。
He's really bad at it, but he sewed name tags on our gym clothes.
超下手だけど 体操着にも　名札　付けてくれたの。
He's a shorty, but he gave me a piggyback ride.
ちびだけど 僕のこと　おんぶしてくれた。
And he taught me magical spell to make the flower sprout.
それに　芽が出る　おまじないも 教えてくれたんだ。
Like this. Woo~ Mambo.
ウ～　マンボって。
Then the flower really sprouted.
そしたらね ホントに芽が出たんだよ。
And he came to watch us at the entrance ceremony too.
それから入学式も来てくれたの。
Look at Marumo's funny face.
ほら　マルモ　変な顔でしょ。
This is Mook.
ムックは　これだよ。
Daddy.
パパ。
Daddy's not here, but we have Marumo.
パパはいないけど でもマルモがいてくれるんだ。
So don't worry about us, Daddy.
だから　大丈夫だよ　パパ。
We love Daddy, but we love Marumo too.
パパは大好きだけど でもマルモのことも大好き。
Yeah, we love Marumo.
うん　マルモ大好き。
Hey, Mook. What should I do?
なあ　ムック。 なあ　どうしたらいいと思う？
You have any good ideas?
何か　いい方法ないか？
You won't talk when I ask you to, huh?
お前 こういうとき　しゃべんねえのな。
Hey.
おい。
Hello, this is Takagi.
はい　高木です。
This is Makimura. Thank you for helping me out the other day.
[TEL]（かな）あっ　牧村です。 先日は　ありがとうございました。
Makimura-san. I'm sorry for
牧村さん。 あっ　先日は失礼しました→
-taking off like that. -No, please don't worry about it.
途中で帰ってしまいまして。 いいえ　気にしないでください。
I was thinking of coming there to visit you now.
それで　これから　そちらに お見舞いに伺おうと思うんですが。
What? Really?
えっ？　ホントですか？
Um...um... but No. Please don't mind me.
あっ　あっ　あっ　いえ　でも　あの 駄目です　お気遣いなく。
But you helped me out on that business trip too, so
[TEL]出張のときも お世話になりましたし→
I'll just stop by real quick and leave right away.
お邪魔したら すぐに帰りますから。→
I'm already almost there.
もう近くまで来てるんです。
What, you are?
えっ　そうなんですか？
What? But, but... No, you can't come.
えっ？　そっ　そんな　そん… あっ　いや　でも　駄目です。
No, no, no. You really can't.
駄目　駄目　駄目 ホントに駄目なんです。
But I heard you weren't doing well so
[TEL]でも かなり具合が悪いって聞いて→
-I got worried. -What? Worried? She said she's worried.
心配になって。 えっ　心配？　心配だって　心配。
Yes, you're right. I feel awful.
あっ　いや そうなんです　最悪なんです　はい。
So you shouldn't come, Makimura-san. You might catch it too.
だから牧村さん　あの 来ない方がいいですよ　うつるし。
I already had mumps when I was little, so I'll be fine.
わたし　小さいころ　おたふく やってますから　大丈夫です。
Is there anything you want to eat or want me to do for you?
何か食べたい物とか 困ってることとかありません？
I'm happy.
うれしい。
Very very happy. I'm happy, but...
すごく　すごく　うれしいな。 うれしいけど。
Tell me anything.
遠慮なく何でも言ってください。
What should I do. What can I do. Um...
どうしたらいい。 どうすればいいだろうか。　え～と。
Actually, I have a favor to ask.
実は　お願いがあります。
[My mom's telling me to take the kids back to their relatives.]
《おふくろ あの子たちを親戚に返せって》
Hey Aya. Take this upstairs for them.
（陽介）おい　彩。 これな　上へ持ってってやれ。→
I got a nice fish, so we'll share it with them.
魚の　いいのが入ったんでな おすそ分けだ。
Okay.
（彩）うん　分かった。 （陽介）よし。
What's wrong?
（陽介）どうした？
I guess Takagi-san's mother is opposed to his taking care of the kids.
高木さんのお母さん　やっぱり あの子たちのこと反対してるって。
She is, huh? Well,
そうか。　あっ　まあな→
it's tough for a man to raise kids by himself.
男手一つで育てるのは 大変だからな。
-Yeah. -Things might work out if
（彩）うん。 （陽介）あいつもな→
he can find himself a nice girl,
誰か　いい人でも 見つかりゃいいけど→
-but that might be difficult too. -Do you think so?
それも難しいだろうしな。 （彩）そうかな。
He didn't have a girlfriend up to now either, did he?
いや　今までだって 彼女　できなかったんだろ？
And now he's suddenly got two kids. Right?
それが　いきなり　２人の子持ちだ。なっ。
Yeah.
（彩）うん。
I can understand why his mother would be worried too.
まあ　お母さんの心配する気持ちも分かるな。
[Marumo's family, isn't he?]
《マルモって家族だよね》
[Even if we don't have Daddy or Mommy, Marumo's family, isn't he?]
《パパやママがいなくても マルモは家族だよね》
[How many times are you two going to practice?]
（彩）《２人とも 何回　練習する気なの？》
[As many times as we can. We're going to answer loudly
《何回も。　ちゃんと マルモに聞こえるように→
so that Marumo can hear us.]
大きな声で　お返事するんだもん》
[Tomoki, hang on.]
《友樹　しっかりしろよ》
[I have a sick child. Please open the door.]
《子供が大変です 開けてください》
[Please, please.] [She told me
《すいません　お願いします》 《「あの子たちが→
all I can do is make the kids feel lonely.]
寂しい思いするだけだ」って 言われて》
[I want to go on living with those kids.]
《俺は　このまま　あの子たちと 一緒に暮らしていきたいです》
Hello.
あっ　お邪魔します。
Oh, Aya-san.
（節子）はい。　あら　彩さん。
If you don't mind, please eat it.
あの　これ よかったら食べてください。
Thank you very much.
わあ。　どうも　ありがとう。 （彩）あっ　いいえ。
How's Takagi-san doing?
あっ　高木さん お加減　いかがですか？
I think he's doing much better, thank you.
（節子）ああ　おかげさまで だいぶ良くなったみたい。
That's good.
そうですか。 （節子）ええ。
Um...
あの。
Um..Mother.
あの　お母さん。
Yes.
はい。
To tell you the truth, Takagi-san...
実は　わたし　高木さんと…。
I mean, Mamoru-san and I are dating.
いえ　護さんと お付き合いしています。
What?
えっ？→
What did you just say?
あっ　あっ あの　ちょっと　今　何て？
Um..What I mean is, Mamoru-san and I are dating, so
ええ　あの　ですから　護さんと お付き合いしていますので→
the two of us will take care of the children.
子供たちのことは ２人で　面倒　見ていきます。
So please put your mind at ease.
だから お母さんには安心していただいて。
Yes.
はい。
Mother.
（かな）お母さま。
Nice to meet you. I'm Mamoru-san's fiancee, Makimura Kana.
初めまして。　私　護さんの婚約者の牧村かなと申します。
-Yes...What? -Fiancee?
はい。　えっ？ （彩）婚約者？
-What! -No way!
えっ！ 嘘！
What's going on? I can't hear.
どうなってんだ　聞こえねえ。
Marumo's popular with the ladies?
マルモ　モテモテ？
He's a disgusting two-timer.
二また　最低。
-Disgusting? -Disgusting.
最低？ 最低。
Um...Your name is Makimura-san, did you say?
あの　えっと　牧村さんと おっしゃいましたかしら。
Yes. And you're
はい。 （節子）あの　護の→
Mamoru's fiancee?
婚約者で　いらっしゃるんですか？
Yes. I work at Akebono Office Supplies
はい。　あけぼの文具に 勤めておりまして→
and I've been dating Mamoru-san.
護さんと　お付き合いを させていただいています。
I see.
そうですか。
What? Oh..I'm..Uh...
えっ？　あっ　いや　わたしは　あの。
Oh, I must have misunderstood.
あっ　あっ わたしの勘違いだったみたいで。→
If Takagi-san's happy, that's all that matters.
あっ　高木さんが幸せなら もう　ホントに　それで。
I'm sorry.
あの　すいません。
Well, then..uh..
あっ　いや あっ　じゃ　あの　わたしは→
I have to go help out at the restaurant so I'll get going.
店の仕込みがありますんで 失礼します。
What? What happened?
何？　何事？
I swear!
（彩）ホントに　もう！→
After I went through the trouble to put on an act for him.
わたしが　せっかく 気を利かせてあげたのに。
-Hey, what's wrong? -Nothing!
おい　どうしたんだよ。 （彩）知らない。
So you're here today to...?
あっ　あの それで　今日は　どんな？
I came see how Mamoru-san was doing,
はい　護さんのお見舞いと→
and I also heard that you were visiting so
お母さまが いらしてるということで→
I thought I'd stop by to say hello.
ごあいさつに。
Well, thank you very much.
あっ　それは恐れ入ります。
I see.
そうなんですか。
So Mamoru had someone like you.
あの　護には　こんな方が。
I'm really sorry.
ホントに　すいませんでした。
For asking you to do something like this.
こんなことを 牧村さんに頼んじゃって。
That's alright. But was it okay?
いいえ。　あっ　でも あれで　よかったんですか？
Pretending to be your fiancee so that you'd have an excuse to decline the arranged marriage.
お見合いを断るために 婚約者のふりするなんて。
You saved me, really. My mom's
ホント助かりました。　おふくろ→
been on my case to go for an arranged marriage.
お見合いしろしろって ホントうるさくて。
I'm glad then.
よかった。
Oh, by the way, who are those children?
あっ　ところで あのお子さんたちは。
What? Huh? Were there children out there?
えっ？　はっ　あっ　あれ？ そんなの　いました？
-Yes. -Hmm...who are they?
ええ。 あれ　何だろ　それ。
Oh, are they child spirits?
あの　あっ　あっ　出た 座敷わらし出たんじゃないすか？
Huh? What? No, that's not it.
えっ？　えっ？ いや　え～と　違う違う　あの→
Oh, my mom's kid...is me.
あっ　おふくろ　おふくろの子供。 は俺です。
Her kid is me, so that's not it.
俺ですから　違います　違います そうじゃないです。
Um...they're relatives. Yes, they're our relative's kids
うんとね　あれ　親戚　親戚だ 親戚の子供が→
who are visiting my mom right now.
あの　今　おふくろと一緒に 遊びに来てんすよ。
Oh, that's who they are.
あっ　そうだったんですか。
But anyway, I'm glad
あっ　でも　取りあえず→
I was able to help you out.
お役に立てたみたいで よかったです。
Thank you so much.
ホントに ありがとうございました。
Don't mention it.
いいえ。
I wonder if girls like Marumo.
マルモ　モテるのかな。
Isn't it strange? He's not good looking.
おかしいね イケメンじゃないのにね。
And he's short.
ちびなのにね。
Yes.
≪（ノック） はい。
Mom. About those kids...
お母ちゃん あの子たちのことだけど→
-Like I said before, I want to... -I'm going home tomorrow.
俺　やっぱり　このまま…。 あした帰るから。
-What? -Make sure you take good care
えっ？ しっかり　面倒　見なさいよ→
of those children.
あの子たちのこと。
Are you really okay with that?
ホントにいいのか？
Thanks, Mom.
母ちゃん　ありがとう。
Makimura-san's a charming person, isn't she?
あっ　牧村さんって すてきな人だったろ？
Yes she is.
ああ　そうだね。
But if I were to pick one, I think I like Aya-san better.
でも　どっちかっていうと わたしは　彩さんの方がいいかな。
Aya-san? Why's Aya-chan's name coming up now?
彩さん？ 何で　彩ちゃんの名前が？
Ah~ I'll finally be free.
あ～　わたしも やっと　これで　解放されるわ。
You were a big help.
いや　ホントに助かったよ。
Good evening. -Wel...Oh, hello.
≪（節子）こんばんは。 （陽介）あっ　いら…　ああ　どうも。
Do you have a minute? Thank you for the fish.
（節子）ちょっといいですか？ これ　ごちそうさまでした。
Oh, it wasn't much.
（陽介）あっ　いえ　お粗末でした。 はい。→
Let me get you a cup of tea. Have a seat.
あっ　お茶でも入れましょう。 どうぞ。
Thank you.
（節子）恐れ入ります。→
Where's Aya-san?
あれ？　彩さんは？
She just left to go shopping.
今　ちょっと 買い物に出ちゃいまして。
Oh, I see.
あっ　そうですか。
I wanted to thank you for everything you did for Mamoru.
あっ　本当に　いつも　護が お世話になっております。
We really haven't done anything.
（陽介）あっ　いえ うちなんか何にも。
Mamoru's doing admirably.
（陽介）よくやってますよ　護は。
But he's a headache for me, doing whatever he wants to do.
（節子）でも 勝手なことばかりで困ります。
Yes. They do whatever they want, don't they, the kids.
はい。 勝手ですよね　子供ってやつは。
Really.
ねえ。
They won't listen to their parents at all.
（陽介）親の言うことなんか 聞きやしない。
But I've been thinking lately.
でも　最近　思うんですよ。
That maybe the only thing parents can do is to watch over them.
親にできることって　結局 見守るしかないのかなって。
You may be right.
そうですね。
Maybe all we can do is trust our children and watch over them.
子供を信じて　見守るしか ないのかもしれませんね。
Yes.
はい。
Have some tea.
（陽介）粗茶ですが　どうぞ。
Looks good.
（節子）あっ　おいしそう。→
Itadakimasu.
いただきます。 （陽介）あっ　どうぞ。
-Watch your step. -Thanks.
階段　気を付けてくださいね。 （節子）うん　ありがとう。
You two take care, okay?
あっ　２人とも　元気でね。
Come and visit Marumo Mommy sometime too.
今度　マルモママんとこにも 遊びにおいで。
Okay. Thank you.
（友樹・薫）うん。 ありがとうございました。
Oh, are you leaving now?
あっ　お帰りですか。
Thank you for everything.
（節子）あっ　どうも 色々と　お世話になりました。
Please continue to watch over
あの これからも　この子たちのこと→
these children.
どうぞ よろしくお願いいたします。
Certainly.
あっ　こちらこそ。
Aya, why don't you go with her to the train station?
あっ　彩 駅まで　お送りしたらどうだ。
Thank you. Mom, you take care of yourself.
すんません。 母ちゃん　体に気を付けてな。
Speak for yourself.
お前の方こそ。
-Come see us again. -It's a promise.
また来てね。 約束だよ。
Yes, promise.
（節子）うん　約束。
Take care.
元気でね。 （友樹・薫）うん。
-Here, I'll take that. -Thank you.
（彩）あっ　お持ちします。 （節子）ありがとうございます。
-Bye bye.
バイバイ。
-Bye bye!
バイバイ！
Thank you, Aya-san.
（節子）彩さん　ありがとうね。 （彩）えっ？
For pretending that you were dating Mamoru
（節子）護と お付き合いしてるなんて→
so that I wouldn't worry.
わたしを安心させるために 嘘ついてくれて。
Oh, you knew?
（彩）あっ　バレてましたか。
There's no way Mamoru could be going out
アハハハ 護が　こんな　すてきな方と→
with someone as lovely as you.
付き合えるわけないもん。
That's not true. Besides, he has a fiancee.
あっ　そんなこと。 あの婚約者の方だって。
Oh, that's a lie too.
ああ　あれも嘘ですよ。
I was opposed to him raising those kids by himself so
わたしが　子供たちのこと 反対したもんだから→
he probably patched things up for the moment.
慌てて取り繕ったんでしょ。
Then you're leaving, knowing everything?
（彩）えっ？　じゃ　全て分かってて 戻られるんですか？
Yes.
ええ。
Mamoru is a hopeless child,
護は　もう どうしようもない子だけど→
but I realized that
でも　あの子たちが→
those children need Mamoru.
護を必要としてくれてるって 分かったから。
Besides, including you and your father,
あっ　それにね　彩さんも お父さまも　そうだけど→
there are so many people who care about Mamoru.
あんなに護のことを 心配してくださる方がいてくれて。
So I decided to watch over him too.
だから　わたしも見守ろうって。
I see.
そうですか。 （節子）うん。
Takagi-san is really trying hard.
（彩）高木さん　ホントに 一生懸命やってると思います。→
They're not even his own kids, and to do that much...
自分の子供じゃないのに あそこまで。→
I'm not sure I'd be able to do the same if I was in his position.
わたしだったら　おんなじこと できるかどうか分かりません。
He's really amazing.
ホントに　すごいです。
Aya-san, please help out Mamoru
彩さん　これからも 護と　あの子たちのこと→
and the children in the future too.
どうぞ　よろしくお願いします。
Yes.
あっ　はい。
Yum.
んっ　うまっ。
Marumo, do you have a girlfriend?
ねえ　マルモって彼女いるの？
Nope. That thing about a fiancee, that's a lie too.
いねえよ。 婚約者とかも　全部　嘘だかんな。
-That's what I thought.
あっ　やっぱり。 やっぱり。
-Don't be saying that.
やっぱりって言うんじゃねえよ→
Seriously...
ったくよ。
Mom's hamburger sure is yummy though.
でも 母ちゃんのハンバーグ　うめえな。
Thanks to this hamburger,
うん　友樹　このハンバーグで→
Tomoki can eat carrots now.
ニンジン 食べられるようになったんだよ。
Good for you.
すげえじゃん。
Carrots have lots of vitamins. You shouldn't be picky.
ニンジンはな　栄養があるんだよ。 好き嫌い言うんじゃねえぞ。
You couldn't eat carrots either.
自分だって食べれなかったくせに。
Huh? How did you know that?
えっ？ 何で知ってんの　それ。　やだ。
Must be Mom. Why'd she have say such useless things.
お母ちゃん。　あっ また余計なこと言いやがってよ。
Okay, I'm gonna write down the okite for the day.
よし　今日のおきて　書いとくぞ。 うん。
Don't be picky. Don't leave food on your plate.
すききらい　いわない　のこさない。
All together now. Don't be
はい　ご一緒に。 （薫・友樹）「すききらい→
picky. Don't leave food on your plate.
いわない　のこさない」
By eating everything on your plate,
うん　残さずに食べるってことは→
you're showing your appreciation to the person who made it, okay?
ご飯を作ってくれた人への 感謝の気持ちだからな。
-Got it.
うん　分かった。 分かった。
Okay. But that mumps was sure a pain.
よし。 でも大変だったよ　おたふく。
-You're all well now, aren't you? -Yeah, once you get it,
もう大丈夫だよね。 ああ　一度ひいたら→
you won't get it anymore. Measles too.
もう　かからないから。 はしかとかもな。
Did you ever have measles, Marumo?
あっ　マルモは はしか　かかったことあるの？
Of course, I...
そりゃ　もちろ…。
Did I have it? Measles?
あれ？　どうだったろ　俺。 はしか？
-What! -Oh no!
えっ！ 大変！
Measles too?
はしかもか？ いや　いや　いや　はしか→
Did I have measles?
えっ　どうだったんだろ　はしか。
What does measles feel like?
はしかって どういう感じなんだろう。
Is this feeling measles? Is this measles?
この　こんな感じが　はしかなの これが　はしかなのかな。
Measles now? I can't tell.
今　はしか？　分かんない ちょっと　待って　待って　待って。
Call Marumo Mommy. Call her, call her.
マルモのママに　電話　電話　電話。
I'll ask her.
聞いてみる。　駄目だ。
Hurry up and answer the phone. Hurry, hurry.
早く出てよ。 早く　早く　早く　早く　早く　早く→
Mom~!
お母ちゃ～ん！